YUNUS YENIGOR

1025 Post Street, San Francisco, CA 94109, Phone: (415) 867-5165, E-mail: yunus@engineer.com Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/yunyeng Github: www.github.com/yunyeng

SUMMARY

3+ Years of experience in full stack web and mobile development. Developed and contributed numerous web and mobile applications as well as web services. Solving real world computer science problems using Algorithms, Data Structures and Statistics background.

EDUCATION

MS, Information Technology Management, Specialized in Business Data AnalyticsApr 2016
Golden Gate University, San Francisco, CA

BS, Industrial and Systems Engineering

Jun 2014

Yeditepe University, Istanbul, Turkey

Course Highlights: Data Science, Linear programming, Mathematical Modeling, Probability, Statistics, Algorithms, Data Structures, Operations Research, Optimization, Markov Chains, Queuing Theory, Financial engineering, Monte Carlo simulation, Statistical Quality Control

PROJECTS

<u>OPEN SOURCE SOCIAL COURSEWARE SYSTEM</u> Implemented Social Media to the Online Education platform. Presented as Undergraduate Thesis. (PHP, MySQL, Javascript)

<u>OPEN SOURCE LIGHTWEIGHT BLOGGING PLATFORM FOR MASSES</u> Instead of Complicated and heavy Wordpress framework, created a more lightweight and less complex blogging platform for the masses. (PHP, MySQL, Javascript) <u>CLARKE-WRIGHT SAVINGS ALGORITHM FOR THE CAPACITATED VEHICLE ROUTING PROBLEM</u> Implemented Savings Algorithm for the capacitated vehicle routing problem in C. Savings algorithm differs from Traveling Salesman problem with limited distributor capacity. (C)

ANDROID MOBILE APPLICATION FOR TURKISH ROCK BAND ZARDANADAM Took an online course from Lawrence Angrave-University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign on Coursera. Created this music band application for Android. (Java, Android SDK)

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Programming: C, Java, Javascript, Python, PHP, R, Matlab, SAS, SQL, NoSQL, HTML/CSS, NodeJS, jQuery, Android. *Good algorithm design skills

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer Intern, FuelX, San Francisco, CA

May 2015 – Oct 2015

- Built brand new Internal Admin tools, and Customer dashboards, systems (Symfony2, MySQL, AngularJS)
- Implemented Internal APIs to convert PHP queries to AJAX queries (Symfony2, AngularJS)
- Fixed bugs and organized and cleaned the old code to prevent future bugs (PHP, Symfony2, jQuery)

Junior Software Developer, Revolvia, Istanbul, Turkey

Feb 2014 - Jun 2014

- Developed API and Web Services, for specific iOS, Android and Web Application (NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB)
- Developed backend of the mobile and frontend of the web application (PHP, Codelgniter, Javascript, MongoDB)
- Developed various facebook applications, including games and survey forms (PHP, Laraval, Symfony, MySQL)

Software Developer Intern, Corvega, Istanbul, Turkey

Dec 2012 - Mar 2013

- Developed the front-end of the Mobile Application for Cheap Flights (Objective C, Java, X Code, Android SDK)
- Developed the front-end of the Windows Tablet App for the LIV Hospital (Visual Basic, C#)
- Designed an Interface for Political Party in Turkey for the National Elections (HTML, CSS)

OTHER SKILLS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Interested and a little experience in Social Engineering, Web Security, Cryptography.
- Contributes to open source projects on GitHub and develops new ones for masses.
- Using open source data online, creates new Graphs and statistical meaning to use in applications.